<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Data Science Unplugged</title>
    <link>http://www.dsup.org/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Data Science Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.dsup.org/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are All Imposters</title>
      <link>http://www.dsup.org/blog/we-are-all-imposters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.dsup.org/blog/we-are-all-imposters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Saghir Bashir &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ilustat.com/&#34;&gt;(www.ilustat.com)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often have flashbacks to a conversation, as a graduate student, with an
internationally renowned award winning statistician. We had been discussing some
issue for which I was seeking advice. It was a fruitful conversation but then they
finished with something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Saghir, I realise that I don&amp;rsquo;t know
anything about statistics.&amp;rdquo; I was stunned. It hit me so hard that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop
thinking about it for weeks, in fact for years. For months I had been struggling
with a ground breaking publication by the said statistician for which they had
been widely recognised. I asked myself if somebody like that doesn&amp;rsquo;t know
anything what chance do I have. It was one of my first experiences of the
&amp;ldquo;imposter syndrome&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than ten years later I found myself analysing some data with various
challenges. The more I looked the more I saw and everything was going in different
directions. I was struggling to get to grips with the magnitude and complexity
of it all. At some point I stopped and felt that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything.
Immediately my mind flashed back to the conversation and I smiled as I finally
understood it. From that moment onwards something changed. I was free and relieved.
I was no longer trying to swim in an ocean that continuously pushed me under with
its waves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I happily embrace my imposter experiences with a passion for different
reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;First and foremost is that the other extreme would be one of arrogance where I
would foolishly believe I knew it all. Bad!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It helps me identify gaps in my knowledge, experience and skills which feeds
my desire to continue learning and developing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It gives me the adrenaline to do my best much like the nervousness before a presentation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am forced to focus on what I really need to know given my constraints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have the power and confidence to consult others without fear and regardless of their
rank or position.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It helps in connecting the dots betweens areas that I feel I know and those that I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a reminder of all of my achievements and milestones, however small they may seem,
that allow me to feel like an imposter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It empowers me to answer questions with &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It lets me switch off from my work when I am living my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It keeps me human.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The renowned statistician had in some sense revealed that they were an &amp;ldquo;imposter&amp;rdquo;.
It was a passive remark without any sense of defeatism or failure. It was matter
of fact. We are all imposters. Let&amp;rsquo;s enjoy it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Master Chef</title>
      <link>http://www.dsup.org/blog/data-science-master-chef/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.dsup.org/blog/data-science-master-chef/</guid>
      <description>Saghir Bashir (www.ilustat.com)
A Master Chef A master chef can transform any set of ingredients into an eye pleasing and appetising festival for your taste buds. Before embarking on their creation, they will begin by understanding the quality and freshness of all the ingredients which will determine the quantities in which they will be fused. Understanding the source and origins will be equally important to them (e.g. type of olives, location grown and extraction method for olive oil).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning R vs Learning a Spoken Language</title>
      <link>http://www.dsup.org/blog/learning-r-vs-learning-a-spoken-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.dsup.org/blog/learning-r-vs-learning-a-spoken-language/</guid>
      <description>Saghir Bashir (www.ilustat.com)
Introduction R has grown in popularity over the years which can be measured by using different metrics, for example, R downloads, the number of packages on CRAN1, participation in on-line communities, books published and so forth. This growth brings with it newcomers who are keen to learn the R programming language.
Learning R, like learning anything else, is a process from which you get what you put into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Certificates of Attendance Using R</title>
      <link>http://www.dsup.org/blog/creating-certificates-of-attendance-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.dsup.org/blog/creating-certificates-of-attendance-using-r/</guid>
      <description>Saghir Bashir (www.ilustat.com)
Sometimes after an event you need to issue certificates to the participants. How do you normally produce several certificates automatically? There are different ways to do it and here we share our approach after a recent community event1. We used R to automatically generate the certificates using R markdown and LaTeX language.
Objective The key objective was to produce PDF certificates that could be emailed to attendees (see above for an example).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Education: Some Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://www.dsup.org/blog/data-science-education-some-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.dsup.org/blog/data-science-education-some-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Saghir Bashir (www.ilustat.com)
Life scientists, economists, ecologists, computer scientists, social scientists, linguists, mathematicians, physcists and many others have or are choosing data science as a career. The treasure trove of backgrounds presents knowledge sharing opportunities and challenges alike. However for newcomers this career transition and continuous development can be overwhelming and leave some of them with feelings of not belonging or lacking competence, characteristics of impostor’s syndrome. Educators, mentors, trainers and managers have a crucial role to play in developing newcomers to become competent and confident data scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>